Kushal Bhowmick

LinkedIn | GitHub

Location: Kolkata, West Bengal, India Email: kushalcr78017@gmail.com | Mobile: +919433822257

ASSISTANT SYSTEM ENGINEER

A Software developer currently working in the 'Finance domain' with over **2 years of experience** in **JavaScript, Core Java, and PL/SQL**. Having a working knowledge of popular frameworks such as **Angular, Nodejs, Express, and SpringMVC** and experience in building RESTful APIs.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages : Core Java, C++, JavaScript, Typescript, HTML, CSS, SQL **Frameworks** : Angular, Bootstrap, Express, Node.js, Spring MVC

Libraries : Material UI, EJS, Handlebars

Databases : MongoDB, MySQL

Dev Tools : Eclipse, Visual Studio Code, Git, TortoiseSVN
Others : Data Structures, Progressive Web Apps

EXPERIENCE

Assistant System Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services

Apr 2021 – Present Kolkata, West Bengal, India

- Designed and developed a dynamic and responsive website using Angular, Typescript, CSS, and Javascript
- Created **REST APIs** to retrieve and display data from database
- Improved website performance and speed through optimization techniques by 55%

Javascript Developer

ROITech

Jul 2020 – Mar 2021 Kolkata, West Bengal, India

- Worked with **SAPUI5 framework** to develop robust frontend applications per client
- Developed a Hybrid mobile application using Javascript, SAPUI5, Apache Cordova, and CSS3

EDUCATION

Narula Institute of Technology

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Instrumentation

Kolkata, West Bengal, India Jul 2015 – Jul 2019

PROJECTS

StoryBook App

Javascript, Nodejs, Express, MongoDB, EJS and CSS

StoryBook

- * Designed and developed a short stories social app with 'Google OAuth' as authentication using **JavaScript, Nodejs, Express, MongoDB, and EJS**
- * A **CRUD application** exposed POST, GET, PATCH, and DELETE HTTP methods using **Express**
- * Utilized responsive design to ensure compatibility across all devices

Tracker App

Typescript, Angular, and JavaScript

Tracker App

* A **Simple TODO - list app** is developed, only the frontend part has been created, **NO** actual backend **(used a fake backend server)** is used for this particular application.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Responsive Web Design(HTML5 + CSS3) by freeCodeCamp
- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures by freeCodeCamp
- Building RESTful APIs with Node.js and Express by LinkedIn